Hello my name is Jake, and today I will
be joined by An, Caiden, and Parsa. Today
we'll be presenting an in-depth overview of our
project VocaFree. VocaFree is a Web Application
that uses YouTube song video links to create an
authentic Karoake experience by separating vocals
from the music of any song and playing just the
instrumental track allowing users to sing any
songs of their choice without the original songs
vocals. It offers lyric translation as well as
romanization to assist the user in singing along
to the lyrics. One of the API's we are using is
the Genius API, this API allows access to a
database of song lyrics, artist information,
and song metadata from the Genius platform. It
allows you to search for songs by title or by
excerpts of lyrics, retrieve artist profiles, and
find lyrics to specific songs. This API is popular
for building music related applications helping
users discover songs and learn about artists. We
are using this API to implement features that
will enhance our user experience. First, it
will allow users to retrieve lyrics for specific
songs so they can sing along with ease. Second,
it enables song searches based on an excerpt
of lyrics helping users quickly find the song
they're looking for. Lastly, the API provides
detailed artist information and song metadata
offering a deeper dive into artist biographies and
song details. Now let's look at some user stories
for the genius features to better understand how
these features will improve user experience for
different users. First let's meet Emma, she's a
singer who loves performing but often finds that
karaoke venues display inaccurate lyrics. With our
Genius integration Emma can access artist verified
lyrics to sing along confidently knowing she's
got the correct words every time. Next is Sarah,
an office worker with a hectic schedule. She
barely has any time to explore new music,
but she often hears Snippets of songs in ads or
at work. With our Genius powered "Snippet Search",
she can enter just a few words she remembers from
songs and the app will instantly find the song
helping her discover music effortlessly. Finally
there's Linda, who's interested in learning about
new artists. Since she has a physical disability
that prohibits her to go out to music events,
she can use our apps "Artist Info" feature
which provides detailed artist biographies and
song metadata from Genius. This lets Linda explore
artist backgrounds and stay connected to the music
industry at home. Hey, I'm Parsa and I'll go over
Open AI API. All right, Open AI API is the most
commonly used Large Language Model API developed
by Open AI and used for ChatGPT. The features that
we're looking to implement are translating lyrics,
romanization/phonetics, and basic lyric analysis.
Alex is passionate about learning new languages
and the ability to translate song lyrics into
English in real time will be helpful for him.
Mike manages a diverse remote team and having
romanized versions of song lyrics will provide
a way for everybody in his team to participate
in karaoke sessions. Emma loves singing and the
lyrics analysis features helps her uncover hidden
meanings behind songs and appreciate the artistry
behind the music. Hi, my name is An. Now this is
the demo of our mid Fidelity Story Board starting
with our landing page. This is the page where our
users can search for a song name; like so, and
these are the suggested songs suggested by our
system. If the user clicks on a song, they are
taken to our karaoke page where they could sing
karaoke to the lyrics shown on the UI. So on the
UI they could see just regular video elements like
the progress bar, the volume of the vocal guide
which will help them sing along to the song. And
they also have buttons to translate their lyrics
as they're singing. If they click on this button
they could see the translated lyrics on the
screen like this. If they want to go back,
simply press the back button. And if they want to
change the language (the translated language) just
press on the button like this. And this button
gives them the option to chat with an AI bot.
For example, if they want the AI to suggest them
songs to sing, they could use this feature. And if
they want to understand more about the songs
they're singing they could use this feature,
to be provided with an analysis of the song by
AI. And last but not least, they also have the
option to cue songs. So, for example they could
search up the name of the song, click on a song,
and a song is immediately added to the queue. Hi,
my name is Caiden and today I will display to you
how the data flows through our karaoke app. First
we'll start with the external user, who will have
the ability to select a song or search for a song.
Upon using the search the user will either be able
to search based on lyrics, or based on the song
title/artist name as expected. When we search
we'll interact with the Genius API and send
the lyric data to Genius. Genius will send the
metadata provided by the song selection to our
YouTube downloader API. That will then send it
over to our UVR (Ultimate Vocal Remover) API which
will then pull the vocal data from our .mp4 song,
so that it can be played back to the user.
Now further, while this is completed,
the user will then request the lyrics in either
English, a phonetic translation, or just a normal
translation. Which will then be sent from
the Open AI API back to the external user.